<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://community-privacy.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://community-privacy.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2026-02-18T02:43:11+00:00</updated><id>https://community-privacy.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Community Privacy Residency (2026)</title><subtitle>privacy and cryptography tools that protect and empower communities from the ground up </subtitle><entry><title type="html">highlights from 2025</title><link href="https://community-privacy.github.io/recap-highlights-2025/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="highlights from 2025"/><published>2025-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://community-privacy.github.io/post3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://community-privacy.github.io/recap-highlights-2025/"><![CDATA[<p>We’re revving up for Community Privacy Residency 2026 in Berlin, Germany! As we start to plan for the next iteration, we look back as well to highlights from the past one:</p> <h2 id="rightscon-conference">RightsCon conference</h2> <p>We attended the four-day <a href="https://www.rightscon.org/program">RightsCon</a> conference, focused on the intersection of human rights and technology, covering issues like counter-surveillance, free speech, and net neutrality. After each conference day, we held internal debrief and sharing sessions, and collectively contributed to notes on more than thirty sessions. Several of our residents also presented sessions at RightsCon, on topics including digital security training, algorithmic bias, and network security.</p> <p>We also attended various satellite events, including the <a href="https://g0v-jothon.kktix.cc/events/g0v-hackath65n">g0v hackathon</a>, and the <a href="https://www.accupass.com/event/2502060951431933743454">Abortion Access and Internet Freedom side-event</a>.</p> <h2 id="community-events">Community events</h2> <p>We organised a post-RightsCon decompression event, featuring partners from <a href="https://a11ylab.com">Accessibility Lab</a>, <a href="https://www.plurality.net">Plurality</a>, and more. The event was attended by seventy-five participants and consisted of:</p> <ul> <li>A yoga session led by one of our residents;</li> <li>An interactive workshop on accessibility on digital platforms, conducted by Nancy Reyes of Accessibility Lab; and</li> <li>A fireside chat on digital rights and democracy, featuring Audrey Tang (Taiwan’s ambassador-at-large for cyber affairs), and moderated by co-organiser Riley Wong.</li> </ul> <h2 id="sharing-sessions-and-workshops">Sharing sessions and workshops</h2> <p>Over the course of the month, we organised workshops, lightning talks, and reading groups, on a range of diverse topics:</p> <ul> <li>Fully homomorphic encryption</li> <li>Zero-knowledge programming in Noir</li> <li>Red teaming policy design</li> <li>Political culture</li> <li>Reverse-engineering</li> <li>Threat modelling</li> <li>Trauma stewardship</li> <li>Self-sovereign identity</li> <li>Digital security</li> <li>Co-design</li> <li>Explorations of peer-to-peer based identity</li> <li><a href="https://github.com/proteus-photos/proteus-paper/blob/main/main.pdf">Provenance detection for AI-generated images (perceptual hashing, homomorphic encryption)</a></li> <li><a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/csrc/media/presentations/2024/wpec2024-3b3/images-media/wpec2024-3b3-slides-antoine-jacques--BBS-sharp-eIDAS2.pdf">BBS# signatures</a></li> <li>Lightning talks on cryptographic metaphors, intellectual property, financial privacy, and more</li> </ul> <p>We also hosted sessions from external guest speakers, including:</p> <ul> <li>Afsaneh Rigot of <a href="https://www.de-center.net">DeCenter</a>, who shared her work on the Design from the Margins framework, and practical advice in facilitation and activism.</li> <li>A virtual guest speaker from Nowhere publishing and bookstore, which published a Mandarin translation of the <a href="https://aw.network">Autonomous Worlds</a> anthology.</li> </ul> <h2 id="local-partners">Local partners</h2> <p>At many points in the program, we collaborated with local partners and community organisations from Taiwan, including:</p> <ul> <li>Representatives from Taiwan’s Ministry of Digital Affairs and OdditySay Labs, who shared their work on the Taiwan Digital ID Wallet; and</li> <li><a href="https://binnextgen.org/community_cafe">University Cafe</a>, a community cafe supporting local youth and activism projects, where we hosted an internal demo day with invited friends.</li> </ul> <h2 id="projects-and-demo-days">Projects and demo days</h2> <p>Our residents’ public-facing contributions have been documented <a href="https://community-privacy.github.io/2025-projects">here</a>, with many of them still under active development. Some of our 20+ projects include:</p> <ul> <li><a href="http://github.com/privacy-ethereum/zkID">Privacy in digital ID systems</a></li> <li><a href="https://github.com/MachinaIO">Machina iO</a></li> <li><a href="https://community-privacy.github.io/taiwan-participatory-democracy/">Taiwan as a model for participatory democracy</a></li> <li>…and many more!</li> </ul> <p>We presented these at two public-facing demo days; videos are available here:</p> <ul> <li><a href="https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLHaQn4UTBU6Eln5grWqHXrXGzB4AcMaJ4">midpoint demo day</a></li> <li><a href="https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLHaQn4UTBU6G-5d_Tn3-Ae00eSV89FvOL">final demo day</a></li> </ul> <h2 id="community-privacy-residency-2026-in-berlin-germany">Community Privacy Residency 2026 in Berlin, Germany</h2> <p>We are actively sourcing locations, partners, and funding for the next iteration of the residency. If you’re interested in collaborating in any capacity – be it as a mentor, volunteer, event space, or sponsor, please reach out!</p> <p>As in the previous iteration, we are committed to keeping the residency accessible, and a big part of this is in heavily subsidising travel and accommodation. Any contribution goes a long way in making this possible:</p> <ul> <li><a href="https://opencollective.com/community-privacy">OpenCollective page</a></li> <li><a href="https://giveth.io/project/community-privacy-residency">Giveth campaign</a></li> </ul> <p>all love &lt;3,<br/> ying tong, riley, and janabel<br/> the CPR co-organizers</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[highlights from 2025, and looking forward to 2026 in Berlin]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">careful optimism</title><link href="https://community-privacy.github.io/janabel-careful-optimism/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="careful optimism"/><published>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://community-privacy.github.io/post2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://community-privacy.github.io/janabel-careful-optimism/"><![CDATA[<p><em>written by: janabel</em></p> <h2 id="bringing-cpr-to-life">bringing CPR to life</h2> <p>earlier this year, i came back from spending <a href="https://community-privacy.github.io/">a month in taipei with a group of 43 cryptographers, activists, designers, and artists working on privacy infrastructure for vulnerable communities</a>. the middle months of my gap year have been a wild sprint – my co-organizers riley and ying tong and i conceptualized, fundraised, publicized, selected the residency cohort, and executed logistics all in the span of late november - late february. if you didn’t hear from me in a while, this is why! &gt;&lt;</p> <p>one of the main things that we wanted to create was a container where all these diverse groups of people could interact, cross-pollinate ideas, and understand each other a little bit more. it was a social experiment to say the least, but one with a purpose — we wanted to ensure that privacy infrastructure was also being built for the people and communities with strong privacy needs.</p> <p>obviously “privacy infrastructure” is incredibly broad, and this model of technological development does not apply universally, but it was our focus. and for selfish reasons, i personally wanted to create a community in which i could talk seriously about both the math behind cryptography as well as the <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/us/us-homeland-security-chief-cancels-two-grants-harvard-university-2025-04-17/">looming rise of an increasingly authoritarian government</a> entangled in <a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/trump-says-minerals-deal-be-signed-next-thursday-after-ukraine-talks-2025-04-17/">all sorts of messy geopolitics</a>, and understand these as intertwined problems to tackle together.</p> <p>across our residency, we wanted to make sure there were i) builders who could do the technical work and execute on the the ideas, ii) designers who could ensure that the designs of technologies made sense and achieved their intended goals, as well as iii) community voices that could lead discussions on experienced privacy threats and give honest feedback on the potential risks of certain technological solutions.</p> <p>while one month was far too short (and many residents felt this as well) to dig super deep, especially across such a diverse cohort, many smaller-scoped projects that came out of it (as already mentioned in <a href="https://community-privacy.github.io/firstpost/">blog post 0</a>) — from research on anonymised digital ID systems; to prototypes for anonymous coordination; to tech policy design methodologies and experiments; to co-design frameworks. you can find all the cool work our residents have done <a href="https://community-privacy.github.io/projects/">here</a>.</p> <h2 id="from-pessimism-to-some-kind-of-optimism">from pessimism to some kind of optimism</h2> <p>beyond the project outputs linked above, this residency also led to major shifts in my energy and worldview. while it was no doubt exhausting to Run Stuff, the main thing i’m bringing back with me from our residency in taiwan is a new sense of optimism.</p> <p>(it also doesn’t hurt that taiwan is quite the model for participatory democracy, with influential ambassadors such as <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Audrey_Tang">Audrey Tang</a> and thriving civic tech communities like <a href="https://g0v.tw/intl/en/portfolio/">g0v</a> (through which Audrey Tang aided the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sunflower_Student_Movement">Sunflower Student Movement</a> through <a href="https://mediarep.org/server/api/core/bitstreams/4ec10874-95f6-4baa-b42b-11a82d18569f/content">digital broadcasting efforts</a>) or <a href="https://info.vtaiwan.tw/#:~:text=More%20than%2028,viewpoints%20and%20experiences.">vTaiwan’s Po.lis being used to push real legislation on Uber regulations</a>), but that’s not the focus of this post.)</p> <p>to be clear, this isn’t the first time i’ve ever felt optimistic. one of the first communities in which i felt a huge amount of optimism was when i attended <a href="https://www.sparc.camp/">SPARC</a> in high school and met some of my best friends to this day. but that was a long time ago, and i have (secretly?) become an increasingly pessimistic person. after all, it’s much easier to be optimistic when you don’t know as much or haven’t experienced as much Not-So-Great stuff. it’s the same phenomenon that occurs when seniors laugh sadly at the innocent, bright-eyed, bushy-tailed freshman at <a href="https://admitted.mit.edu/cpw">MIT’s Campus Preview Weekend (CPW)</a>. it’s the same phenomenon when older adults tell students to stop thinking so hard about what kind of impact they want to make on the world, and to just recognize that a job is a job.</p> <p>as i grew older and learned of more Criticisms that made sense to me — the optimism was even harder to dig up. from the weird incentives of academic institutions (where i would see talented researchers prioritize publication maximization over research motivations), to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Department_of_Government_Efficiency">dominating power of successful tech CEOs</a>, to criticisms of generalized <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/centrist/comments/17rh00g/whats_your_biggest_critique_of_the_democratic/">political</a> <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/centrist/comments/17s7ldy/what_is_your_biggest_critique_of_the_republican/">views</a> — i began to lose hope in being able to find the “right” spaces in the world. it seemed like most global issues people were talking about were intractable in the spaces i saw around me. time to time i drifted back into optimistic bursts — maybe i saw people working on an intersection of technology and civic society in a way that was energizing (e.g. civic tech communities like <a href="https://g0v.us/">Taiwan’s g0v</a>), maybe i saw a novel way to apply X technology for Y cause (e.g. market making strategies to sustain <a href="https://www.gridmatic.com/">VC-independent clean energy grid optimization</a>). but then they would start to feel far away, i would find new holes to poke at on either their side or mine, and i would feel a new sense of pessimism all over again.</p> <p>in the context of creating this residency, this pessimism looked like a mild personal disillusionment with the cryptography space at large (which to be clear, has plenty of people i admire). i felt like either i) privacy was being treated as a vague ideology where end goals were not super clear, or ii) privacy technologies were being imagined and prioritized purely for financial incentives, or iii) privacy technologies were being designed without considering the privacy needs of communities who care about it because they need it the most (community and labor organizers, journalists, political activists, etc.).</p> <p>of course, one must give credit where credit is due — a lot of technological advancements happen “by accident” (e.g. the contribution of the <a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/nvidia-how-the-chipmaker-evolved-from-a-gaming-startup-to-an-ai-giant-140140110.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAGwYRS7IXNE22wZiHWpCy3ZyjR6kLjq8V0O6DSDXejwpqfajL-VME41Uk9YSPGbjw1_Pc46-7ZSRtIVGL-6JP1aKUZq_hXyaB75MmHPSbLTKtt8Id8K50N2dXbnWWSz1JqAAtnkrQKMwPEoTJst15sjcXnKcQ3O8hPnXX1LUIrHW">gaming industry to GPU development</a>, now a core technological component of the modern AI revolution), and it is very hard to predict the effects of frontier technology anyways (see The Internet). similarly, these spaces that i became personally disillusioned with were no doubt fundamental to this residency being able to exist in the first place – whether on the technological side, the educational side, or the financial side. i also know plenty of wonderful souls in these cryptography spaces and plenty of souls who have quietly poured their <em>money and hard work</em> into major civic technology efforts for the public good – something that others may not know about from the outside, or sadly assume the contrary based on their external identity. still, i felt that something was missing for me in these spaces, whether it was a personally compelling narrative around why privacy matters and why cryptography helps, or a deeper connection to people with certain privacy needs.</p> <p>but in the end, it’s far too easy to poke holes, focus on the negative, play the blame game, etc. — especially for someone like me. doing so only pushed me further into a cycle of doom. i’ve learned it’s much harder to poke holes in things and harness energy to do something about those holes. this second option i would call “careful optimism” – having a high affinity for both grounded truth-seeking and fantastic-ideal-reaching. i think some people use “<a href="https://dictionary.cambridge.org/us/dictionary/english/cautious-optimism">cautious optimism</a>” but that feels different, because the amount of optimism or standard for improvement is not less here. i believe careful optimism is a scarce but valuable resource.</p> <p>in helping create this residency, i finally felt like i got to tap more into careful optimism. i felt liberated from the cynicism that i had been trapped in, and it was energizing to create what i felt was a missing space to fill the hole – a space bridging both technologists and privacy advocates, a space to collectively ground and develop privacy technology in new directions. it was hard and scary at times, and there are still a lot of unanswered questions, but doing it with other people who believed strongly in the vision made it more possible than i imagined &lt;3.</p> <p>while i’m celebrating this current optimism, i also remember reading plenty of short tech twitter takes that glorify things like “optimism” and “agency” in a way that historically made me feel worse about not “just being optimistic”. i don’t want this post to be more of that. one thing these short takes misses is a realistic path towards optimism in the first place. for me, the foundation of my experience building this residency was my high-trust friends and communities that heard my wild idea and told me that i should go for it – they helped incubate this wild idea in a safe space. &lt;3. i would be lying if i said being optimistic was some magical switch i just decided to turn on. instead, it was highly environment-dependent and a communal effort. my friend yush sent me <a href="https://anson.substack.com/p/how-to-coparent-baby-ideas">this post</a> that sums it up pretty well – i remember reading it and being convinced, but it’s hard to fully understand something like this until you actually experience it.</p> <p>aside from the exercise of creating the residency itself, i think my newfound optimism and reason to continue working in cryptography derives from i) discovering concrete examples of projects that energize me (like pushing <a href="https://github.com/eu-digital-identity-wallet/eudi-doc-architecture-and-reference-framework/discussions/408">scalable ZK integration for digital ID</a>), ii) working with people who lead by example (hi ying tong and riley!!!) who i feel safe around, and iii) finding a community of people who share a healthy level of skepticism around “technology”-maxiing while continuing to be curious and eager to act and improve it in the ways they want to see.</p> <p>all in all, i’m feeling re-energized, happy to be back in the US, and ready to get some work done :)</p> <hr/> <p><em>A huge thank you to all the <a href="https://community-privacy.github.io/partners/">sponsors</a> of the Community Privacy Residency for making this work possible!</em></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[reflections on bringing CPR to life & importing optimism from my month in taiwan]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">community privacy blog</title><link href="https://community-privacy.github.io/firstpost/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="community privacy blog"/><published>2025-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://community-privacy.github.io/post1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://community-privacy.github.io/firstpost/"><![CDATA[<p>hey everyone!</p> <p>we’re super excited to kick off the community privacy blog, an offspring of our community privacy residency. the first edition of our month-long residency in 2025 focused on designing and building privacy infrastructure in collaboration with marginalized communities. you can find more information about the residency on the homepage here.</p> <p>as an extremely abbreviated recap of our residency, a group of 43 technologists, designers, cryptographers, writers, activists, and researchers (not mutually exclusive!) came together across the span of 4 weeks and jammed on various projects related to privacy for communities. our community collaborated on projects presented during demo day, hosted workshops for each other, led discussion groups and paper reading groups, and much more.</p> <p>we celebrated and continue to celebrate the diversity we had across our residents, from domains of expertise to formats of work to communities that they belong to and look out for. for example, workshop topics ranged from co-design methodologies and threat modelling sessions to hands-on workshops analyzing encrypted internet traffic and mini-lectures on the math behind cryptographic primitives like FHE.</p> <p>we’re also excited to share that a bunch of public projects emerged from the residency, ranging from <a href="https://pitch.com/v/anon-coordination-k6d4yx/fc1ad40d-fb65-4d70-a5af-58cdabfef6c2">anonymous community coordination tools</a>, research on use-cases for <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1zP25V5vyM7FF1PF_Icm9ROwQxvXLiFJ167KSj9SAmCk/edit?slide=id.g332a7367e5b_0_60#slide=id.g332a7367e5b_0_60]">collaborative and private AI model training</a>, <a href="https://hackmd.io/@plaintextdesign/S1Lz7bPiJe#/">UX research on Shamir’s secret sharing-based account recovery</a>, and so much more. an ongoing list of our projects and descriptions can be found <a href="https://community-privacy.github.io/projects/">here</a>.</p> <p>at the same time, the residency community created so much that cannot possibly be captured by projects outputs and documentation alone, including small and big-group conversations, unanswered questions from those conversations, evolving dynamics observable within the physical community, and much more.</p> <p>we believe some of the most important developments in technology spaces start out illegible in format, which is why writing is so important as a medium for communication. our hope is that this blog can help translate some of the more ethereal concepts that our organizers and residents have been discovering in this space. we hope you join us on this journey!</p> <p>all love &lt;3,<br/> ying tong, riley, and janabel<br/> the CPR co-organizers</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="meta"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[kicking off our community privacy blog!]]></summary></entry></feed>